The “tpc.csv” data file contains the thermal performance curve parameters used in the analysis. The file “tpcs_meta.csv” describes the data fields. R code and data are available at https://github.com/HuckleyLab/ThermalStress/.
DESCRIPTION
We used the terms “thermal optima” and “Topt” to search the literature for datasets that included all three thermal performance curve parameters (CTmin, Topt, and CTmax) or that permitted estimates of these parameters. Our final data includes a total of 384 TPCs (289 species) across multiple taxa. These TPCs vary in the type of performance measured and in the level of biological organization (see Table S1). We refer to five compiled datasets labeled by the taxonomic group and level of performance represented. The ant performance dataset describes foraging activity for 22 genera of ants, where Topt is estimated based on the proportion of ants foraging as a function of ground surface temperature (Guo et al., 2020). CTmin and CTmax were replaced with minimum and maximum foraging temperatures, respectively, when they exceeded CTmin and CTmax estimates. The lizard performance dataset describes lizard sprint speed for 77 populations of 66 species, combining data from two studies (Huey et al., 2009; Muñoz et al., 2016). The fish growth dataset describes growth rates for 18 populations in three species of salmonid fish (Elliott & Hurley, 1995; Jonsson et al., 2001; Larsson et al., 2005; Forseth et al., 2009). 
      The final two data sets focus on the temperature dependence of fitness (r: intrinsic rate of population increase). The insect fitness dataset describes r for 67 populations (61 species) of insects, updating data (Huey & Berrigan, 2001; Frazier et al., 2006) that been used in numerous analysis of climate change impacts (Deutsch et al., 2008 and subsequent papers) with additional recent observations (Rezende & Bozinovic, 2019). The plankton fitness dataset describes r for a total of 266 populations in 184 species of phytoplankton (Thomas et al., 2012, 2016). 
      It is important to appreciate the heterogeneity in biological levels and types of performance for interpreting the different patterns in TPCs (see DISCUSSION). Note that performance is a rate for four of the five datasets but is a proportion for the ant performance data. Topt values were estimated by fitting TPC curves to performance measured at multiple constant temperatures. For ants and lizards, CTmin and CTmax estimates were based on temperature ramping experiments. For the other taxa, CTmin and CTmax were estimated by extrapolating the fitted TPC curves (Deutsch et al., 2008). The TPC functions and fitting methods differed among the initial publications. The Rezende and Bozinovic (2019) insect dataset used a TPC function with a long left tail that was not designed for estimating CTmin. We thus re-estimated CTmin, Topt, and CTmax for this dataset using the fitting algorithm from the plankton dataset (Thomas et al., 2012). Quality control criteria for these TPC estimates are described in Table S1.

